Blake French

San Diego, CA • 208-380-0086 • <u>blakefren@gmail.com</u> www.linkedin.com/in/blakefrench • <u>blakefren.ch</u>

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 8 years of experience in critical data-centric roles, including large-scale online advertising and semiconductor manufacturing. Design and maintain large-scale production systems, involving billions of records each, and train / enable relevant models. Experienced in multiple languages such as Python and C++. Background in machine learning and physics.

EXPERIENCE

Google San Diego, CA April 2020 – Present

Software Engineer

- Protect children online by classifying advertisements into an age-appropriate ratings scheme (AAA), which
 restricts ads with inappropriate topics from serving to minors.
- Create and maintain systems to enable AAA on multiple Google and third party platforms serving billions
 of users.
- Analyze the performance of machine learning models and launch improvements.
- Primary engineer on Google search and shopping, including launch / roadmaps / design, analysis, pipelining, etc.; these projects increased AAA child coverage by 10x.
- Design and improve team infrastructure; realized 50% alert reduction and significantly improved automation by designing a new scheduling platform, while reducing on-call toil.
- Mentor junior engineers, and participate in regular code reviews, team on-call duties, and interviewing.

Micron Technology, Inc.

Boise, ID

August 2015 - April 2020

Senior Control Systems Engineer

- Automate manufacturing reactions to process faults and anomalies, with the goal of reducing scrap, product variance, and RMAs, via modeling in fault detection and classification systems (FDC).
- Created and maintained FDC systems, and enhanced FDC system functionality with plugins and feature additions.
- Worked with process engineers to model manufacturing processes and establish suitable process limits.
- Realized multi-million dollar savings across product lines at multiple factories with FDC systems.
- Designed / implemented FDC integration on new thermal compression bonder process; significantly reduced faults and excursions.
- Global SME for new tool / sensor integrations and non-standard control systems solutions.
- Worked with R&D groups to provide FDC coverage for new product integrations.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

May 2023

• Master of Science in Computer Science – Machine Learning

Idaho State University

May 2015

- Bachelor of Science in Physics
- Bachelor of Science in Music

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python, C++, SQL, C#, Go
- Machine learning, mapreduce, statistical process control techniques
- Python libraries: Torch, Tensorflow + Keras, pandas, sklearn

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Armada Corps, Inc. Boise, ID December 2016 – August 2019 Founder, Board Member

- Make high-level decisions for the organization with the rest of the executive team.
- Developed website, wrote non-profit incorporation documents, and created other public-facing documents.